religioustolerance.org 2001-12-14

# OCRT Privacy statement

### 

**Click Here to Visit our Sponsors.**

### Overview:

### Why a privacy statement?

Surveys have indicated that almost all users of the Internet are concerned about their personal privacy while surfing the web. ******1** One way of addressing these concerns is for individual web sites to publish their privacy policy. Unfortunately, many have not yet done so.

The _Ontario Consultants on Religious Tolerance_ has created this privacy statement in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to our readers' privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website: **ReligiousTolerance.org**. We have also added some material on our site's contents and external links. 

This statement also applies to **ReligiousTolerance.com** which automatically redirects readers to ReligiousTolerance.org 

If you have any concerns, please [Email us.](mailto:ocrt_ge@cgo.wave.ca?subject=PRIVACY) [ocrt@religioustolerance.org](mailto:ocrt@religioustolerance.org) 

### Information that we can access:

| | **PairNetworks:** This is the company that hosts our web site in Pittsburgh PA. Like essentially all other web hosting services, they collect information such as IP addresses, time of access, essay URL, etc. from all of the visitors to the web sites on their computers. These data are stored in daily log files in our directory. We are unable to read these files; they cannot be viewed in any programs that we have available. However, we do indirectly access these data once a week. We analyze the files using the _Analog2_ program. This program supplies us with a statistical report indicating the total number of hits, the distribution of hits as a function of hour of day and day of week, and the numbers of hits that each of our essays received. The statistical report prepared by this program contains no identifying information; it tells us absolutely nothing about individual visitors to our web site.   
---|---  
| **Hitbox.com:** About 10 of our most popular essays contain a Hitbox.com logo. Hitbox collects information about each visitor to these essays. They make selected data available to us in various forms. Almost all of the data (level of traffic, the search engine from where they are referred, the browsers that they use, etc.) are only reported as totals or averages of all visitors. For example, Hitbox tells us that 59% of our visitors use Microsoft Internet Explorer, 41% use Netscape and 1% use other browsers. Almost all use version 4 or 5; 3% use version 3; less than 1% use other browsers. This sort of information helps us design our pages for optimum viewing. The _Last 100 visits_ subsection of their _visitor_ section does list individual host computer names and IP addresses. However, as a matter of policy, we only viewed this screen on one occasion, in order to see its format.  
| **HumanClick:** Our chat page uses software developed by _HumanClick_. When you are chatting with one of us, the software displays your IP address which identifies your Internet Service Provider (e.g. 123.456.654.321). It also lists your browser program (Netscape, Internet Explorer) and version number. We do not log or record these values. _HumanClick's_ privacy policy is at: <http://www.humanclick.com/company/privacy.htm>   
  
### What information do we share?

The only information that we share is on our web site for all to see:

### External links from our web site:

|  **All external links:** We have no influence over, and thus cannot be responsible for, the privacy practices or the content of other Web sites.  
---|---  
| **Hate sites:** This site contains thousands of links to other sites. Almost all of them are benign. However, a very few of the sites that we link to contain material that exhibits extreme religious hatred. We link to them as examples of unethical and despicable web sites.   
| **Ibill.com:** We appeal for donations on our "help us" page. This is linked to _Ibill.com_ , a company that accepts credit card data and passes it on to credit card companies. _Ibill_ provides an accounting package that enables us to find out the amount of each donation, the Email address, and the name of each person donating. For reasons of privacy, we do not read or otherwise use any of this information other than the amounts donated, (except once when we were asked to cancel a recurring billing). We realize that some people who donate wish to do so anonymously, for religious or other reasons. We feel that to read, record, or otherwise use their name or Email address would be a violation of that anonymity.   
  
### Child visitors:

A poll of our readers has indicated that 0.2% are under 13 years of age. The _Children's Online Privacy Protection Act_ became effective on 2000-APR-21. **2** It requires compliance from commercial web sites which:

We do not believe that our site qualifies under either of these criteria.

### Public Forums

This site makes a message board available to its users. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information in the sense that anyone, anywhere in the world has access to it. You should exercise caution when deciding to disclose any personal information. 

### Security

This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. We had an unpleasant break-in to our office computer in 1998. Somebody modified a few of our files related to homosexuality. We have since installed a commercial firewall to prevent recurrence. A second and probably unrelated event occurred in early 2000. Someone apparently broke into the computer of our web hosting service and briefly added an audio file -- a song about vampires. 

### Banner advertisements:

Our main source of revenue are the numerous banner ads found on menus and essays on our web site. As of 2001-JUL-10, we use the following banner ad companies:

### Contacting this Web Site:

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this Web site, you can contact:  
Bruce Robinson, coordinator  
_Ontario Consultants on Religious Tolerance_  
PO Box 514  
Wellesley Island NY  
13640-0514  
Email: [ocrt@religioustolerance.org](mailto:ocrt@religioustolerance.org)    
Fax: (613) 547-9015

### Reference:

  1. " _Protecting Online Privacy_ ," at: <http://www.witchvox.com/fritz/privacynotes.html> 
  2. "How to comply with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Rule," at: <http://www.ftc.gov/bcp/conline/pubs/buspubs/coppa.htm> 

**Originally written: 1999-NOV-25  
Latest update: 2000-JUN-22  
Author: B.A. Robinson**

####
